Let's do it next time.
（愛花）真広。
（不破真広）ん？
Mahiro?
（愛花）キスとは　どういう感じが
するものなのですか？
What does a kiss feel like?
Why do you want to know that?
なぜ　そんなことに興味を持つ？
（愛花）私は　したことがないので→
Because I've never had one.
初めてのときに
戸惑わないためにも。
And I'd prefer to avoid hesitating when I have my first.
（滝川吉野）僕もしたことないなぁ。
I haven't had one yet, either...
It's hardly surprising that you haven't, Yoshino.
（愛花）吉野さんは
していなくて当然です。
あっ…。
（愛花）それで　どうなんですか？→
So, what does it feel like?
たまには　兄らしい助言の一つも
してください。
You could give me some brotherly advice once in a while.
キスとか　１０年早ぇよ。
You're too young to talk about kissing.
もうちょっと　女らしく
肉が付いてから言いやがれ。
When you actually become a woman, ask me again.
He's useless, after all.
やっぱり使えない人ですね。
Why the hell is she asking now, without even a boyfriend?
どうせ　相手もいねぇのに
何言ってやがる。
I wouldn't allow her to have one
いても許さねぇ。
そこは許せよ。
You should allow that, at least.
No way... She's my little sister.
ダメだろ　俺の妹だぞ。
Is that really a valid reason?
それは　ダメな理由になるのか？
なるだろ。
It is.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
From: Girlfriend
Subject: Next Time
Yoshino,
since it'll be the first
time for both of us,
let's do it next time.
One day,
（ナレーション）＜　ある日
一人の少女が　唐突に殺された＞
a girl was suddenly killed.
＜　ある日　魔法使いの姫君が→
One day,
the princess of the mages
樽に詰められ　島流しにされた＞
was stuffed into a barrel and exiled to an island.
Return, return.
（男たち）戻れ　戻れ　果実　果実。
Fruit, fruit.
ガシャン
（男たち）美しい　美しい→
Beautiful, beautiful.
Fruit, fruit.
果実　果実。
ガシャン
＜　そして　ある日…＞
And one day...
Return, return, return, return, return....
（男たち）戻れ　戻れ　戻れ→
戻れ　戻れ　戻れ→
戻れ　戻れ　戻れ。
A battle surpassing time and space,
＜復讐と魔法を巡る→
時間と空間を超えた戦いが
始まった＞
wrapped in revenge and magic, began.
Episode 2
He Said
She Was Very Beautiful
ふん！　くっ！
ガン！　ガン！
ほらよ。
いらないよ　金持ってないし。
Here you go.
I don't want it...
I don't have any money.
You're too honest.
律儀だな。　そう深刻になるな。
Don't worry so much.
言ったろ
俺が世界を救ってやるって。
I told you...
I'm going to save the world.
突拍子もなさすぎて
ついていけないんだよ。
It's all so crazy, I'm having a hard time keeping up.
So basically, that fruit-thing
さっきの果実みたいな物体
鎖部一族が→
is part of the thing the Kusaribe clan wants to summon, right?
目覚めさせようとしているものの
一部…　なんだよな。
Yeah.
ああ。　今　全国各地で飛び出して→
They're emerging all over the country and trying to gather at one location.
１か所に
集まろうとしているあれは→
Once they do, they'll combine and regain their true form.
全部集まることで
元の形を取り戻し　復活する。
そうなれば終わりだ。
If that happens, we're finished.
この世の理は
すべて　ひっくり返される。
This world's logic will be completely overturned.
この有様じゃあ
復活する前に終わってないか？
At this rate, aren't we already finished?
あれが出てくると
黒鉄病ってのに襲われるんだろ？
When those things pop up, don't people contract the Black Iron Syndrome?
町の１０や２０の犠牲で
済んでるうちは→
It's not so bad yet when there are only ten to twenty victims in the whole town.
まだマシなんだよ。
（葉風・通信）吉野といったな？
えっ？
Yoshino, was it?
（葉風）案ずるな　私は健在だ。
Fear not, for I am well.
I, Kusaribe Hakaze, the strongest mage of all time,
この史上最強の魔法使い→
（通信）鎖部葉風が好きにはさせん。
will not let them get away with this.
もっかい整理していいですか？
Could I go through this once more?
There's a clan of mages named the Kusaribe,
鎖部とかいう
魔法使いの一族があって→
and an argument within the clan led to a power struggle.
その内部で
意見の対立　権力争いがあった。
Precisely.
（葉風・通信）そのとおりだ。
結果→
As a result,
you, Hakaze, the clan's princess heir, fell for Samon's trap,
一族の姫君であった葉風さんは
左門という男の罠にかかり→
ろくに魔法を使えない孤島に
閉じ込められてしまった。
and are now stranded on a desert island, barely able to use magic.
（葉風・通信）
まぬけのように言うな！→
Don't make me sound stupid!
I'm the only one with the power to stop Samon's plan!
左門の企みを止める力を持つのは
私だけ！
でも
今　使える魔法は　人形を通して→
But your only current magic is the ability to speak through a doll...
話をすることぐらい…　ですよね。
Right?
Exactly.
（葉風・通信）そのとおりだ。
はぁ…　もういいです。
Never mind.
Do you finally understand?
（葉風・通信）やっと理解したか。
物分かりの悪い男だな。
You don't understand things very well, do you?
さて　行くか。
どこに？
Well, then let's get going.
Where?
すべての始まりの場所だ。
あっ…。
To the place where everything started.
葉風　約束は守ってもらうぞ。
Hakaze, you'd better keep your end of the bargain.
（葉風・通信）うん？　ああ
貴様の家に戻ってきたのか。→
Huh?
Oh, you're back at your home?
Well, then...
ならば
その瞬間が訪れた場所へ行け。→
Go to the exact location of the incident.
I can follow them from there.
そこから跡をたどれる。
開けろ。
Open it.
（葉風・通信）
外見と逃走経路ぐらいは→
I should be able to detect their appearance and escape route.
割り出せるだろう。
それ以上となると条件が厳しいが。
If you need anything further, it may be a bit more difficult.
What's wrong?
どうした？
あっ　いや…。
Oh, nothing...
ピピピッ
カチッ
（心の声）
≪ここが　すべての始まりの場所≫
This is where it all began.
It was here that Aika-chan...
≪この場所で　愛花ちゃんは…≫
We're here, Hakaze.
着いたぞ　葉風。
（葉風・通信）魔具を。→
Talismans.
ステンレス鋼のナイフが
あったろう。→
There's a stainless steel knife, isn't there?
Tracking a killer requires a special form of magic.
殺人犯のトレースは
やや特殊な魔法だ。→
A knife works well.
刃物が向いている。
魔具？
A talisman?
An item with magical power sealed within.
魔法の力を封じた道具だ。
Magic?
魔法？
葉風は　なんらかの理由で→
In the event that she couldn't use her magic,
魔法が
使えなくなったときのために→
Hakaze hid talismans in various places,
あらかじめ
あちこちに隠しておいたんだ→
where no one in her clan would find them.
一族の誰にも
気付かれないようにな。
そいつを　直接
肌に触れる形で身につける。
You put them on, so they touch your skin.
葉風の音声で
許可が出されていれば→
Then you can use simple magic,
once Hakaze gives the verbal command.
俺でも　単純な魔法が使える。
However,
ただし…。
コンコン
あっ。
使える回数は限られているがな。
you can only use them a certain number of times.
本物の魔法使い相手に
こんな小道具で対抗できるのか？
Can we stop a real mage with these little things?
（葉風・通信）できなければ
誰にも　左門を止められん。→
If not, no one will be able to stop Samon.
Only magic can counter magic.
魔法を破れるのは魔法だけだ。
葉風　魔法の許可を出せ。
（葉風・通信）よし　魔具を放すな。
Hakaze, get permission for magic.
Very well.
Don't release the talisman.
Hear my words, and grant my wish.
我が言葉にて聞き届けよ。
樹の中の樹　大樹の中の大樹→
Tree within the tree,
great tree within the great tree,
the tree that has existed since the beginning, Tree of Genesis.
（通信）
始まりにありし　はじまりの樹よ→
この地より　人の理を外れし者→
Find the one who has strayed from logic,
血を欲せし者の跡をたどれ！
find the one who is seeking blood.
聞き届けろ。
Grant this spell!
（葉風・通信）
１年ぐらい前の事件となれば→
If this incident occurred about a year ago,
it will take some time for me to collect the killer's information.
残留した犯人の情報を
収集するのに時間がかかるぞ。
大した時間じゃないなら
かまわねぇよ。
I don't care, so long as it's not too long.
I've already waited a year
俺は　もう　１年待ってる→
to kill Aika's murderer with my own hands!
愛花を殺したヤツを
この手で殺すのをな。
That's right...
≪そう　真広は
葉風さんと取り引きした≫
Mahiro made a deal with Ms. Hakaze.
He would help her, in return for her aid
≪手を貸すかわりに→
１年前　妹を殺した犯人を
魔法で見つけろと≫
in magically finding the one who killed Aika a year ago.
お前の心意気には→
I'm sure your spirit would
天国の愛花ちゃんも
感激するだろうね。
impress even Aika in Heaven.
Don't be stupid.
バカ言うな。
The dead don't feel happiness or sadness.
死んだ人間は
喜びも悲しみもしない。
俺は　愛花を殺したヤツが→
I just can't forgive the fact that Aika's killer hasn't received the judgment they deserve.
なんの裁きも受けない不合理を
許せないだけだ。
だから
俺は　魔法の力を手に入れる。
That's why I will use magical power.
That's why I will help Hakaze
だから　葉風に手を貸し
ついでに　世界を救ってやる。
and save the world in the process.
Ms. Hakaze, are you sure you can trust this guy?
葉風さん　こんなヤツを
信用していいんですか？
Our interests align, so he won't betray me.
（葉風・通信）利害は一致している。
なら　裏切らん。→
It's advantageous that the fool cares so for his sister.
妹思いのバカで　むしろ好都合だ。
It seems she also has a questionable personality.
≪この人も
性格に問題がありそうだな≫
吉野。
ん？
Yoshino...
The city will be quarantined soon.
町は　じき封鎖される。
早く逃げろ。
You should hurry and flee.
えっ？
僕は　手を貸さなくてもいいのか？
What?
You don't need my help?
Won't your parents be worried about you?
親だって心配してるだろ。　それに→
And also,
こんな　やばい状況のときこそ→
at a time like this, you should be with your girlfriend.
彼女のそばにいてやれよ。
Besides, you never got along with Aika.
お前　愛花と仲悪かったしな
この先　俺につきあう義理はねぇ。
You have no obligation to stick with me.
I guess that's true...
そう…　だろうな。
そうなんだよ。
Yeah.
Take these... They're talismans.
持っていけ　魔具だ。
えっ？
これがあれば　黒鉄病も防げるし→
With these, you won't develop Black Iron Syndrome,
葉風の発動許可も
出してあるから→
and since Hakaze's unsealed their power,
防御と高速移動が可能だ。
you'll be able to use them for defense and high-speed movement.
望む力をイメージすれば
魔法が発動する。
If you imagine the power you want to use, the magic will be invoked.
Also, if you see lots of butterflies around suddenly, be careful.
ああ～　それから　蝶が
やたら舞いはじめたら注意しろ。
あれが
あの果実が飛び出す前兆の一つ。
That's one of the signs that a fruit will appear.
果実の香りにあてられて→
Eggs and caterpillars respond to the fruit's smell and develop instantly.
卵やサナギが
一気に成虫になるんだ。
じゃあな。
Well, see ya!
I'll be back after I've killed Aika's murderer.
愛花を殺したヤツをぶっ殺したら
戻ってくる。
そのとき　彼女に会わせろ。
Introduce me to your girlfriend then.
そうだな。
Yeah.
そのときは
ちゃんと　彼女を紹介するよ。
When that happens,
I'll introduce you to her.
"Save the world in the process," huh?
≪ついでに
世界を救ってやる…　か≫
He doesn't care what happens to the world.
≪真広にとって
世界が　どうなろうとかまわない≫
≪愛花ちゃんを殺したヤツを
見つけられるなら→
If it meant finding Aika's killer,
迷わず世界を滅ぼすだろう≫
he wouldn't hesitate to destroy the world.
Tomorrow's promise
≪永遠に来ない明日の約束≫
will never come.
≪この世界では
いくつの明日の約束が→
I wonder how many of tomorrow's promises have disappeared,
音もなく消えうせたんだろう≫
as though they never existed.
Takigawa Yoshino...
（葉風・通信）滝川吉野…
魔具までくれてやって→
You trust him enough to give him a talisman?
信用できるのか？
吉野とは　長いつきあいだ。
I've known Yoshino a long time.
（葉風・通信）私も　左門や
一族の者とは　長いつきあいだぞ。
I've also known Samon and the others for a very long time.
しかし　今は…。
But now...
Don't compare me to a despicable woman like yourself.
（通信）お前みたいな
いけ好かない女と一緒にするな。
"Despicable" also quite accurately describes you.
いけ好かなさでは
貴様も相当なものだぞ。
Shut up.
黙れよ。
どうやら　結果が出そうだぜ。
Well...
Looks like we'll get some results.
缶詰とか
持っていった方がいいのかな。
I wonder if I should take some canned food...
でも　荷物になるし…　ん？
But that'll just increase the weight.
（山本）
この地域は　３０分後に閉鎖ね。→
This region will be closed in thirty minutes.
オーケー。　それまでに
不破真広との再接触を図るから。
Okay.
I'll try to reestablish contact with Fuwa Mahiro within that time.
[TEL]（アナウンス）
お客様の　おかけになった電話は→
The number you have dialed is in an area with no service...
Mother
電波の届かない所にあるか…。
ピッ
Mother
（葉風・通信）どうだ？　真広。
How's it going, Mahiro?
≪待ったぞ　このときを≫
I've been waiting
for this moment.
≪間もなくだ≫
Any minute now,
≪これで　犯人の手がかりが…→
I'll finally be able to get
手に入る！≫
a clue about the killer!
≪これだけたっても
救急車一つ来ないなんて…≫
So much time has passed, but there's not a single ambulance.
（回想）((政府は　必死に
隠しているが　いつまでもつか))
The government's doing what they can to hide it,
but they won't be able to forever.
((ここらも
何か理由つけて封鎖されるぞ))
They'll think up some reason to quarantine this area, too.
Does the government plan to give up on this city?
≪政府は　この町を
見捨てるつもりなのか？≫
こいつら…。
These guys...
すいません　これから　いろいろ
入り用になってくると思うんで→
Sorry.
I have a feeling I'll really need this soon,
回収させてもらいます。
so I'm taking it back.
"Have everything make sense again," huh?
辻褄を合わせる…　か。
≫（山本）やること　えぐいわね。
Well, that's pretty harsh.
バシッ！
うっ！
（山本）死体から　金を盗むなんて→
Stealing a wallet off a corpse...
さすがは　不破真広の友人ね。
いい？　少しでも抵抗したら→
Nothing less from a friend of Fuwa Mahiro.
If you resist at all,
まず　脚を撃ち抜くから。→
I'll start by blowing a hole in your leg.
Tell me everything you know about the mage.
全部話しなさい
魔法使いについて。
Do you two know where Kusaribe Hakaze is?!
君たちは
鎖部葉風の居場所を知っているの？
≪魔具に直接　触れ　イメージ…≫
Touch the talismans and imagine...
≪防御と高速移動！≫
Defense and high-speed movement!
がはっ！→
とりあえず　大丈夫そうかな。
Looks like I'm okay for now...
≪この子　なんて名前だっけ？≫
This girl...
What was her name?
石川…　石沢？
Ishikawa? Ishizawa?
Guess I won't need to know again.
もう二度と知る必要もないけれど。
≪もう二度と…≫
Never again.
パリン！
うっ！
マジか!?
Seriously?
Found you!
見ぃ～っけ。
（葉風・通信）犯人捜しが
こんなふうにつながるとは…。→
I didn't anticipate finding such a connection to the the killer.
これは　予想外だ。
This was unplanned...
誤解するなよ。
責めるつもりはねぇよ。
Don't get me wrong.
I have no intention of blaming you.
（通信）犯人を押さえるのに　お前が
必要ってのは　はっきりしたんだ。
It's become apparent that I'll need you in order to catch the killer.
事件は１年前か…。
The incident was about a year ago?
That was before I was exiled!
そのころは　まだ
島流しにされていなかったのに→
気付かずにいたとは…。
I can't believe I didn't know.
（通信）樽詰めにされる
まぬけな姫君じゃ　しかたがねぇよ。
Since you're a stupid princess who got stuffed in a barrel,
it can't be helped.
（葉風）そのまぬけの力がないと
困るのは　お前だぞ！
And you're the one who'd be in trouble without a stupid princess's help!
俺の協力がなくて困るのは
お前の方だろ。
Aren't you the one who'd be in trouble without my help?
あっ…　人？
A man?
ふっ　案外　早く会っちまったな。
Seems I bumped into one sooner than expected.
What happened?
（葉風・通信）どうした？
本物の魔法使いだ。
It's a real mage.
One of Samon's dogs?!
（葉風・通信）左門の犬か！
（夏村）少年　なぜ　ここにいる？
Boy,
what are you doing here?
お前こそ。
左門の言いつけで現地調査か？
What about you?
Checking out the region on Samon's orders?
なるほど。　気の利いた答えだ。
I see.
That was a perceptive answer.
その魔法　どこで覚えた？
Where did you learn that magic?
樽の中でさ。
In a barrel.
Really.
（夏村）そうか。→
それは　狭くて大変だったな。
That must have been very constricting and difficult.
ほう…　やる気　十分だなぁ→
Guess you're prepared,
spear-guy.
槍男。
（葉風・通信）槍!?→
Spear?
Mahiro, don't fight him head-on!
真広　まともに戦うな！→
おそらく　そいつは　鎖部夏村。→
Most likely,
that's Kusaribe Natsumura.
手ごわい…　手ごわいぞ！
He's tough...
A very tough opponent!
Well, then...
それなら　ここで倒しておこうぜ！
I'll beat him right here!
（山本）吉野く～ん。
Yoshino!
滝川吉野く～ん。
Takigawa Yoshino!
ふふっ
なめてもらっちゃ困るわ。→
Can't let you underestimate me, now can I?
寂しい大人の女はね→
Lonely grown women
have many toys as friends.
いろんな道具が　お友達…　なのよ。
You see?
あっ！　ごほっ！
ごほっ！　ごほごほっ！
ごほっ！　ごほっ！
（山本）
さあ　どこに隠れているのかな？
Well,
I wonder where you're hiding...
なんたらと煙は
上へ上へ　上がっていくのよね。
The smoke keeps moving higher and higher.
It's freezing!
寒っ！　８０デニールのタイツ
はいてくればよかったわ。
I should have worn my 80-denier tights...
あら　いつの間に。
Oh, when did you arrive?
返してくれない？
Could you return that to me?
子供には　手に余るおもちゃ。→
It isn't something little kids should play with.
下手に撃てば　相手は死ぬのよ？
If you aren't careful, you could kill someone.
あなたは
ここに来るまでに　何を見ました？
Exactly what
did you see before coming here?
What?
蝶が吹雪のように舞い
それ以外の生き物が金属化し→
Butterflies flying in hordes.
Every other living thing metallicized.
怪しい果実が飛び出す…　そんな→
And a suspicious fruit flying around.
Is there anything that couldn't happen
この世の関節が
外れてしまった中で→
起こりえないことがあるとでも？
while time is out of joint like this?
この世の関節って…
「ハムレット」か。
Time is out of joint?
Quoting Hamlet?
教養あること言うわね。
That's fairly knowledgeable.
≪この子は撃てる→
He's willing to shoot...
冷静に　当たり前に…≫
Calmly,
like it's natural.
≪とんだ狼じゃない≫
He's no ordinary kid.
うっ！
ドカッ！
ふぅ…　高速移動と防御か。
High-speed movement and defense, huh?
やっぱり
これぐらいが　せいぜいか。
Apparently, that's the limit.
取り引きしませんか？
Let's make a deal.
取り引き？
A deal?
やっぱり僕は→
It seems I
真広を一人　放っておくわけには
いかないようです。
can't leave Mahiro by himself, after all.
（夏村・通信）
左門殿　果実の飛んだ地で→
Mr. Samon,
I've met a boy who hadn't metallicized at a site where fruit has appeared.
金属化していない少年に
出会いました。→
鎖部の魔法を使えるようです。
He appears able to use Kusaribe magic.
（左門）やはり姫様が…。→
The princess really did
あの孤島から
ここへ手を伸ばせるとは…。→
manage to reach this far from the island.
ふっ。　これが持って生まれたものの
差かもしれんな。
Perhaps this is the difference of those born to the power.
（夏村・通信）どうされます？
What shall we do?
Capture him.
捕らえろ。
分かっていると思うが　殺すな。
I'm sure you understand this,
but don't kill him.
（山本）
今は　取り引きに応じるけど→
I'll agree to the deal for now,
君は　早く
この件から手を引いた方がいい。
but you really should separate yourself from this case.
いくら親友でも　妹の復讐で
狂ってるヤツにつきあってたら→
Even if he's your friend,
you'll never have enough lives to hang around someone crazed
by revenge for his sister.
命がいくつあっても
足りないわよ。
そうですね。
つきあってる彼女に→
You're right.
Even my girlfriend used to tell me
真広とつきあってると
ろくなことはありませんよって→
that no good would come of hanging out with Mahiro.
言われました。
「ました」って　過去形よね。
Used to? Past tense?
あっ…。
いえ。
No,
黒鉄病とは無関係です。
it's unrelated to the Black Iron Syndrome.
１年ほど前
突然会えなくなりまして。
A year ago, I suddenly became unable to see her anymore.
≪１年ほど前って
不破真広の妹も…≫
A year ago?
That's when Fuwa Mahiro's sister...
「たとえ幾千幾万の兄があり→
Forty thousand brothers
could not, with all their quantity of love,
その愛情すべてを
寄せ集めたとしても→
おれ一人のこの愛には
到底　およぶまい」。
make up my sum.
「怒りよ　火と燃えて→
O anger, turn to heat, dry up my brains!
おれの脳味噌を
干あがらせてしまえ！→
This mad thirst for vengeance must be quenched...
お前の狂気の怨み→
存分に晴らさずにおくものか」!!
ガキッ！
≪「いかに
冷酷無惨な仕返しになろうとも」≫
no matter how cruel and merciless I must become!
待って！　まさか　君も
愛花って子の復讐を!?
W-Wait!
Do you plan to avenge this Aika, also?
僕は　真広とは違います。
I'm not like Mahiro.
復讐したって　犯人を殺したって→
Even if I were to get revenge,
even if I were to kill her murderer,
不合理は不合理のままです。
being irrational is still irrational.
何も変わりません。
何一つ戻ってきません。
Nothing would change.
Nothing would return.
一体　死んだ彼女のために
何ができるんでしょうね。
What can I do for a dead girlfriend, anyway?
ひょっとすると
この関節が外れた世界でなら→
Maybe I can find the answer in this world
見つかるかもしれません。
where time is out of joint.
kimi to miteta nagareboshi oikakete
Chasing the shooting star that we saw together
Reaching this place all alone
hitori bocchi konna toko made kiteta
Hiding the feelings I wanted to express to you
kinou kimi ni ienakatta kimochi o
kotoba no naka kakusu no
within words
tooku hanarete itemo douka todokimasu you ni
No matter how far we are separated,
please let it reach you
kono michi no saki ni matsu unmei nante
The fate waiting for us down this road
is not yet known
ima wa mada
dare mo mada
shiranai kedo
by anyone
To the future drawn by numbed fingers
kajikan da yubisaki de egaita mirai he
With you we can make it
kimi to nara ikerutte
nee sonna ki ga shiteta nda
That's what I feel
kitto
with certainty
The Tree of Genesis?
はじまりの樹？
A mighty tree that rules all reason.
（葉風）あまねく理をつかさどる
大いなる樹だ。
A magic that needs civilization?
文明が必要な魔法なんて…。
This, too, is just a kind of fate.
これも　何かの因果さ。
Is that all you have?
（夏村）それで終わりか？
I cannot die this easily...
これくらいで
死んでる場合じゃねぇよな…。
You believe that is within reason?
（葉風）世の理に
かなうことだと思うのか？
Miracles are irrational by nature.
奇跡なんて不合理ですから。
Episode 3
There Are Things
Even Magic Cannot Do